In the name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful.
O you wrapped in garments (Prophet Muhammad)!
Stand (to pray) all night, except a little—
Half of it, or a little less than that,
Or a little more. And recite the Quran with measured recitation.
Verily, We shall send down to you a weighty Word.
Indeed, the hours of the night are more effective for worship and more upright in speech.
For you by day is prolonged occupation.
And remember the name of your Lord and devote yourself to Him with complete devotion.
Lord of the East and the West; there is no deity except Him, so take Him as Disposer of affairs.
And be patient over what they say and avoid them with gracious avoidance.
And leave Me with the deniers, the possessors of ease [in life], and allow them respite a little.
Indeed, with Us are shackles and burning fire,
And food that chokes and a painful punishment—
On the Day the earth and the mountains will quake and the mountains will become a heap of sand flowing down.
Indeed, We have sent to you a Messenger as a witness upon you, as We sent to Pharaoh a messenger.
But Pharaoh disobeyed the messenger, so We seized him with a ruinous seizure.
Then how can you fear, if you disbelieve, a Day that will make the children white-haired?
The heaven will break apart therefrom; ever is His promise fulfilled.
Indeed, this is a reminder; so whoever wills may take to his Lord a way.
Indeed, your Lord knows that you stand in prayer almost two-thirds of the night or half of it or a third of it,
And a group of those with you. And Allah determines the night and the day.
He knows that you will not be able to continue it and has turned to you in forgiveness,
So recite what is easy [for you] of the Quran.
He knows that there will be among you those who are ill and others traveling through the land,
seeking [something] of the bounty of Allah and others fighting for the cause of Allah.
So recite what is easy from it and establish prayer and give zakah,
And loan Allah a goodly loan. And whatever good you put forward for yourselves, you will find it with Allah.