In the name of Allah, the Entirely Merciful, the Especially Merciful.
and the most powerful, saying,
Indeed, for you in the day is a long morning.
And remember the name of your Lord and turn to Him in turn.
Lord of the East and the West, there is no god but He, so take him as a guardian.
And be patient with what they say, and leave them a beautiful place of refuge.
And leave Me and the deniers, the owners of grace, and give them a little time.
Indeed, We have a place of refuge and a place of fire,
And food that is full of bitterness and a painful punishment.
On the Day when the earth and the mountains will be turned upside down, and the mountains will be a
as We sent to Pharaoh a messenger.
Then Pharaoh disobeyed the messenger, and We took him as a slave and a slave.
So how can you be afraid if you disbelieve on a day when He will make the children a slave?
The sky is made to be a place of rest for him. His promise was fulfilled.
Indeed, this is a reminder. So whoever wills, take to his Lord a way.
Indeed, your Lord knows that you stand less than a third of the night and half of it and a third.
And its half and its third and a group of those with you. And Allah decides the night and the day.
He knows that you will not be counted, so He has repented against you. So read what is easier than the Qur'an.
He knows that there will be among you a disease, and others will struggle in the land seeking the bounty of Allah.
And others fight in the cause of Allah. So read what is easy for you.
And establish prayer and give zakat and lend to Allah a good debt.
And whatever you offer for yourselves of good, you find it with Allah. It is good and the greatest reward.
And ask forgiveness of Allah. Indeed, Allah is Forgiving, Merciful.